{
    "id": "54df69a2f2b7418da89a8832f79c654a",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It's time you ........................... that stereo repaired.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it's time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "got",
                "had got"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She acts .......................... she knows his secrets.",
            "description": "Either could be used to say what a situation seems like.",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time she ............................. a job.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it's time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "finds",
                "found",
                "has found"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I ............................. longer hair.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after I wish to express regret about the present.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It seems ..................................... the cat was injured in the fall.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It is high time she .............................. smoking.",
            "description": "A simple past is used after it is high time to refer to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "gives up",
                "gave up",
                "give up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It would have been better if you ............................... a doctor.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "consult",
                "consulted",
                "had consulted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It would be better if you .................................. the police.",
            "description": "In type  2 conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "inform",
                "informed",
                "had informed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I prefer classical music ............................... heavy metal.",
            "description": "We prefer x to y.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "than",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I .............................. wait than leave.",
            "description": "Prefer is followed by a to-infinitive or gerund. Would rather is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "prefer",
                "rather",
                "would rather"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I prefer calling my friends ................................. writing to them.",
            "description": "Prefer + ing form/to-infinitive + object + rather than + infinitive/ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "than",
                "rather than"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ................................. riding to driving.",
            "description": "Prefer can be followed by an ing form or  to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "would rather",
                "prefer",
                "rather"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}